<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>longlinht.github.io/</title>
   
   <link>http://longlinht.github.io/</link>
   <description>编程，读书，思考，旅行，与机器对话，与人交谈，对神发问，探索，体验人生美丽的风景</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Tao He</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>13个问题测试你对这个世界的无知有多严重</title>
	  <link>//13-questions-test-your-ignorance</link>
	  <author>Tao He</author>
	  <pubDate>2021-04-22T04:54:12+08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//13-questions-test-your-ignorance</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>在Factfulness这本书中作者一开头就抛出13个对事实认知的问题，以此测试读者对这个世界的认知，因为我已经读完了这本书，我觉得这些问题值得将其单列出来，有兴趣的可以做做这些测试题，文末附有答案，相信我你的成绩不一定好过大猩猩，问题列表如下:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-text" data-lang="text">1. In all low-income countries across the world today, how many girls finish primary school? 
   A: 20 percent    B: 40 percent    C: 60 percent 

2. Where does the majority of the world population live? 
   A: Low-income countries    B: Middle-income countries    C: High-income countries 

3. In the last 20 years, the proportion of the world population living in extreme poverty has … 
   A: almost doubled    B: remained more or less the same    C: almost halved 

4. What is the life expectancy of the world today?
    A: 50 years    B: 60 years    C: 70 years 

5. There are 2 billion children in the world today, aged 0 to 15 years old. How many children will there be in the year 2100, according to the United Nations? 
   A: 4 billion    B: 3 billion    C: 2 billion

6. The UN predicts that by 2100 the world population will have increased by another 4 billion people. What is the main reason? 
   A: There will be more children (age below 15)    B: There will be more adults (age 15 to 74)    C: There will be more very old people (age 75 and older) 

7. How did the number of deaths per year from natural disasters change over the last hundred years? 
   A: More than doubled    B: Remained about the same    C: Decreased to less than half 

8. There are roughly 7 billion people in the world today. Which map shows best where they live? (Each figure represents 1 billion people.) 

9. How many of the world’s 1-year-old children today have been vaccinated against some disease?
   A: 20 percent    B: 50 percent    C: 80 percent 

10. Worldwide, 30-year-old men have spent 10 years in school, on average. How many years have women of the same age spent in school? 
   A: 9 years    B: 6 years    C: 3 years 

11. In 1996, tigers, giant pandas, and black rhinos were all listed as endangered. How many of these three species are more critically endangered today? 
   A: Two of them    B: One of them    C: None of them 

12. How many people in the world have some access to electricity? 
   A: 20 percent    B: 50 percent    C: 80 percent 

13. Global climate experts believe that, over the next 100 years, the average temperature will … 
   A: get warmer    B: remain the same    C: get colder
</code></pre></div>
<p>Here are the correct answers:</p>

<p>1: C, 2: B, 3: C, 4: C, 5: C, 6: B, 7: C, 8: A, 9: C, 10: A, 11: C, 12: C, 13: A</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>重读Sapiens</title>
	  <link>//read-sapiens</link>
	  <author>Tao He</author>
	  <pubDate>2021-04-18T04:54:12+08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//read-sapiens</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>两年前读过《人类简史》的中译本，去年年终和今年年初一口气读完了《未来简史》和《今日简史》的英文版，就一直惦记着干脆把《人类简史》的英文版再读一遍，今年过年时本来想一鼓作气读完，但是中间又读了《The Black Swan》，就一直没顾上，最近坐地铁通勤，断断续续终于又读了一遍，不得不说，再读英文版，依旧有新的收获。不管从写史的风格，思路，框架，格局，还是文笔，都是一等一的杰作。</p>

<p>且看开篇这个段落：</p>

<p>Years Before the Present </p>

<p>13.5 billion Matter and energy appear. Beginning of physics. Atoms and molecules appear. Beginning of chemistry. </p>

<p>4.5 billion Formation of planet Earth. </p>

<p>3.8 billion Emergence of organisms. Beginning of biology. </p>

<p>6 million Last common grandmother of humans and chimpanzees. </p>

<p>2.5 million Evolution of the genus Homo in Africa. First stone tools. </p>

<p>2 million Humans spread from Africa to Eurasia. Evolution of different human species. </p>

<p>500,000 Neanderthals evolve in Europe and the Middle East. </p>

<p>300,000 Daily usage of fire. </p>

<p>200,000 Homo sapiens evolves in East Africa. </p>

<p>70,000 The Cognitive Revolution. Emergence of fictive language. Beginning of history. Sapiens spread out of Africa.</p>

<p>45,000 Sapiens settle Australia. Extinction of Australian megafauna. </p>

<p>30,000 Extinction of Neanderthals. </p>

<p>16,000 Sapiens settle America. Extinction of American megafauna. </p>

<p>13,000 Extinction of Homo floresiensis. Homo sapiens the only surviving human species. </p>

<p>12,000 The Agricultural Revolution. Domestication of plants and animals. Permanent settlements. </p>

<p>5,000 First kingdoms, script and money. Polytheistic religions. </p>

<p>4,250 First empire– the Akkadian Empire of Sargon. </p>

<p>2,500 Invention of coinage– a universal money. The Persian Empire– a universal political order ‘for the benefit of all humans’. Buddhism in India– a universal truth ‘to liberate all beings from suffering’. </p>

<p>2,000 Han Empire in China. Roman Empire in the Mediterranean. Christianity.</p>

<p>1,400 Islam. </p>

<p>500 The Scientific Revolution. Humankind admits its ignorance and begins to acquire unprecedented power. Europeans begin to conquer America and the oceans. The entire planet becomes a single historical arena. The rise of capitalism. </p>

<p>200 The Industrial Revolution. Family and community are replaced by state and market. Massive extinction of plants and animals. The Present Humans transcend the boundaries of planet Earth. Nuclear weapons threaten the survival of humankind. Organisms are increasingly shaped by intelligent design rather than natural selection. The Future Intelligent design becomes the basic principle of life? Homo sapiens is replaced by superhumans? </p>

<p>我也看过不少历史类的书籍，没有一个作者像赫拉利这样，寥寥数言，已经清晰的勾勒出人类历史的基本脉络，并且文字有趣，简洁。坦白讲，自柏杨先生《中国人史纲》的开篇后，好多年没再看到这么好的历史类段落了。</p>

<p>书中所论述的一些观点之新颖，视角之新奇，思想之深刻，足可让赫拉利本人创立一个学派，而这些观点和视角完全值得细数一番：</p>

<p>人类相较于其他哺乳动物都是早产儿。</p>

<p>在地球上曾经存在过很多个人种，现在只剩下智人一支，而其他人种的消亡智人有脱不了的干系，就如一些巨形陆生动物的消亡也与智人的出现脱不了干系一样。</p>

<p>使用火，吃上熟食，依旧是人类节省消化能量，促进大脑进化的关键。</p>

<p>人类的崛起，或者说是成为这个世界的主宰的关键，不是会使用工具，而是智人虚构出了一些不存在的东西，如神鬼，宗教，国家，法律，公司等，这是消亡的其他人种和其它动物所没有的。</p>

<p>人类在农业革命之前可能活的是最轻松和健康的，从那之后人类就进入了无尽的辛劳和焦虑，直到今日这种状况也并没有改善，只是换了一种表现形式。</p>

<p>人类的秩序是想象出来的，包括钱，因为人相信这些是真实存在的。</p>

<p>汉谟拉比法典和人权宣言都不能细细推敲，如严格说来都是胡说八道。</p>

<p>书中如上述的一些观点和论述都有更多的细节，可参阅原文，几乎每一条都新是新思路，新视角，使人总有拍案叫绝的冲动。文字也是好文字，使我一个可通读英文书籍没几年的人也感觉没有刻板，不觉晦涩。</p>

<p>好书就该为其写一篇读后感，虽是最俗套的做法，但还是写下了自己的一些感受和领悟。今后回看也好有个参照。</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>读《未来简史》</title>
	  <link>//read-homo-deus</link>
	  <author>Tao He</author>
	  <pubDate>2020-10-25T04:54:12+08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//read-homo-deus</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>读《未来简史》一直都在我的读书计划中，最近终于可以安排上了，本来的计划是先把《人类简史》的英文版先读一遍，再接着读三部曲中的第二部，这样可以像看电影似的接上，因为赫拉利的书观点性很强，《人类简史》的中文版我已经读过一遍，所以不太想再把那些观点再嚼一遍，于是直接在Kindle上开始看《未来简史》，通勤中，飞机上，睡觉前，半个月时间，不知不觉看完了。如同《人类简史》一样，是一本让人手不释卷的好书。看完后，总有一种不吐不快的感觉，因此有了此文。
英文版的封面与中文版不同，醒目的红色大字&quot;Homo Deus&quot;是主标题，而中文版的主标题却是英文版的副标题&quot;A Brief History of Tomorrow&quot;,正好主副标题颠倒，对&quot;Homo Deus&quot;的翻译是&quot;从智人到智神&quot;, 看完全书，感觉还是翻译为&quot;从智人到智神&quot;更为贴切，&quot;未来简史&quot;感觉是病句，当然认为前者更贴切的原因不仅仅是咬文嚼字，而是这个标题才是整本书的主旨——未来会有一个新的脱胎于智人的种族（Homo Deus）诞生，或取代智人的地位，或导致智人灭绝。Homo Deus延续了《人来简史》的风格，或者说延续了赫拉利的写史风格, 宏大的叙事，精炼的语句，几乎是我读过的所有历史类，社会类书籍里面独有的一种，开篇就有惊人之语，至少在我读过的书里面没有遇到类似的论调:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>For thousands of years the answer to this question remained unchanged. The same three problems preoccupied the people of twentieth-century China, of medieval India and of ancient Egypt. Famine, plague and war were always at the top of the list. For generation after generation humans have prayed to every god, angel and saint, and have invented countless tools, institutions and social systems – but they continued to die in their millions from starvation, epidemics and violence. Many thinkers and prophets concluded that famine, plague and war must be an integral part of God’s cosmic plan or of our imperfect nature, and nothing short of the end of time would free us from them.</p>

<p>Yet at the dawn of the third millennium, humanity wakes up to an amazing realisation. Most people rarely think about it, but in the last few decades we have managed to rein in famine, plague and war. Of course, these problems have not been completely solved, but they have been transformed from incomprehensible and uncontrollable forces of nature into manageable challenges.</p>

<p>Forthe first time in history, more people die today from eating too much than from eating too little; more people die from old age than from infectious diseases; and more people commit suicide than are killed by soldiers, terrorists and criminals combined. In the early twenty-first century, the average human is far more likely to die from bingeing at McDonald’s than from drought, Ebola or an al-Qaeda attack.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>翻译提炼下截取的这三个段落:</p>

<p><strong>饥荒，瘟疫和战争一直是世代困扰智人的三大难题，智人在第三个千年第一次战胜了饥荒，瘟疫和战争，或者说基本控制了这三大难题.</strong></p>

<p>的确是新颖的观点，第一次发现可以从这个视角来看人类的历史，开篇的这些惊人之语，只是开胃菜，也是论述智神诞生的铺垫，因为当智人战胜了这三大难题后，智人的使命或者说智人未来的福祉会是什么，追求永生还是获取极乐？这个问题明显是一个无限开放，无限发散的问题，整本书就是沿着这条主线展开的，而从智人脱颖而出的智神的诞生也是探寻这个问题过程中导致的结果之一，书中在探寻这个问题的过程中逐步展开更多的命题，抛出振聋发聩，令人耳目一新的论点，让人震惊，叹息，恐惧，并引起深思。</p>

<p>因为我是差不多半个月的时间陆续读完全书，对书中内容的印象是碎片化的，写下此文时也不是正襟危坐，思绪连贯的行文，而是在手机或电脑上迅速记下一些思绪的片段，着重对一些触动我的部分展开讨论，现遴如下：</p>

<p><strong>人类有灵魂而动物没有灵魂是错的， 灵魂是不存在的</strong></p>

<p>这个论点既不是无神论，也不是唯物主义，而是经过大量的心理学实验的论断，智人从动物中脱颖而出并最终统治这个世界当然不是因为独有的灵魂，而仅仅是因为智人可以想象并编造出这个世界上没有的东西，并因此而为之达成规模无限扩大的合作，这才是智人胜出的关键，之所以这里说到的是智人，而不是人类，是因为一些与智人同源的一些人类分支已经灭绝了，而可怕的事实是灭绝的原因可能与智人直接相关。 乍一看，这个观点仅仅是对上一部《人类简史》中观点的呼应，但书中讨论了很多心理学实验，进一步佐证和加强了这个观点。并且这个观点也将智人拉下了神坛，顺便给人文主义一击。</p>

<p><strong>人文主义(Humanism)不过是另一种宗教而已，数据(Dataism)主义也是</strong></p>

<p>这个不仅对人文主义是沉重一击，也击到了我，人文主义不是人类曙光吗？引领人类摆脱宗教，战胜愚昧。作者有很多理由，多个维度告诉你它仅仅是另一种宗教，这是一个激怒无数人的论调，因为人文主义不单单是一种主义，在当下语境，它是和自由主义，民主，市场化，法律等等的观念产物紧密相连，是目前人类社会的基石。而往往认为它是和宗教完全不同的。看到这个论调的时候我猛然想到汤因比的《历史研究》里曾把社会主义和基督教作类比，但仍旧无法立刻接受把人文主义与基督教作类比。而这个论调更要命的是否定智人的自由意志，而自由意志是所有人类法律，市场，良知，道德的基石。很多抛弃人文主义的人开始倒向数据主义，而数据主义得益于日益飞速发展的计算机互联网技术，凭借惊人的算力，AI的逐步演进，生物技术的突破，俨然成为了另一种宗教。人有丰富的情绪，在人文主义者看来这是人的价值所在，独特之处，而在数据主义者看来不过是一些人体的生化反应而。孰对孰错，孰优孰劣，交给时间吧！</p>

<p><strong>智神会导致智人的消亡，如同智人导致了非智人人类的消亡一样</strong></p>

<p>智神如何导致智人消亡我们没看到过，但是智人导致其他人类的消亡却有考古和历史证据，而智神们是脱胎于现在的人类，也许通过基因技术，数据特权，悄无声息的崛起。所谓的超人诞生，智人消亡，这不禁让人联想到纳粹主义，想到尼采，但都不能与之同日而语，也许这个过程是和平演进，底层的民众如大梦初醒时一切都已经晚了，因为智神已经出现，无论从智力，体力，智神都完全碾压智人，智人比任何一个时代都绝望，“富不过三代，穷不过三代”，这个规律不再适用，智人厄运不止，最终消亡。这种图景也许是很多普通人无法接受的，但是果真如赫拉利所言，智人又能怎样呢？你只能期盼赫拉利错了。</p>

<p>当然整本书绝不仅仅是以上的这些观点，只是以上的这些观点最触动我，也能呼应很多以前看过的书，是一次很好的对思维方式和观念结构的SPA，至于书中的一些观点的对错其实并不重要，启发和击中我才是最重要的，其中所提供的一些视角和思考方法也是独一份，独特到我很快要被它安利了，但是我又要保持警惕，不至于陷入&quot;赫拉利主义&quot;。放眼全球，貌似赫拉利在中国最火，似乎我们又狂热的认为如获至宝，就跟很多年前马克思主义被引进时，而事实上赫拉利如美国很多畅销书作家一样，只是提出了一种新的观点和研究成果，既不是真理，也不是终极预言，却引来很多国内互联网大佬和学者的热烈讨论，实属奇观，如果仅是讨论学术，那真是太好了，说明国内思想学术之活跃，如果因为其他，那也是奇观！</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>读《决断力》</title>
	  <link>//read-make-a-better-decision</link>
	  <author>Tao He</author>
	  <pubDate>2018-10-16T02:20:12+08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//read-make-a-better-decision</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>今年可能年景不好，运气不佳，再加上自己昏招频频，感觉今年非常不顺，也发现自己很不会决策，没有很好的决断力。于是就想找一本决断力相关的书来看看，找了一下，还果然有这个书名的一本书，而且豆瓣上评价不错，于是发送到Kindle，趁着地铁通勤的时间很快看完了，因为是中文版，看起来比较快，感觉正本书还是比较平实的，很多决策的方法可操作性强，因为这次使用了Kindle自带的标注功能，在看的过程中随手标注了重点和一些精彩的段落，整本书看完后，对标注和笔记做了整理，现记录出来：</p>

<p><strong>正常情况下，你的思维几乎会对所有发生的事情做出直觉反应并形成某种看法。</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>在你的精神世界里，很显然，你极少被某个问题难住。</p></li>
<li><p>在尚未熟悉某个人之前，你已经产生了喜欢或厌恶的感觉；</p></li>
<li><p>当然，你也可能不知道为什么自己会信任或怀疑陌生人；</p></li>
<li><p>或是在未对某一公司做出任何分析评估的情况下就认定它一定会成功。</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>聚光效应</strong></p>

<blockquote>
<p>卡尼曼认为，人们匆忙做出结论，是由于我们对眼前的信息关注过多，却对视线之外的信息不加考量。</p>
</blockquote>

<p>从本质上来讲，这又恰恰是决策的核心难题：灯光内的东西很少会是我们做出一个好的决定所需要的全部,但我们时常会忘了调整聚光灯的方向。 人们在决策时遇到的难题，即主观偏见和非逻辑性。</p>

<p><strong>研究人员通过对比发现&quot;决策流程更为重要——比分析重要 6倍&quot;。</strong></p>

<p><strong>唯一被广泛采用的决策方法是列出利弊清单。</strong></p>

<p><strong>影响决策的屏障</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>思维狭隘</p></li>
<li><p>限制你的选择范围</p></li>
<li><p>证实倾向</p></li>
</ul>

<p>当人们有机会从现实世界中搜集信息时，人们更可能去搜集那些支持他们已有的看法、信仰和行动的信息</p>

<p>证实倾向令人感到些许恐惧的地方在于：当我们希望某件事情是真实的时候，便会关注支持这件事是真实性的信息，然后，当我们从中得出自己想要的结论时，还要庆幸自己做了一个非常理智的决定。天啊！</p>

<ul>
<li><p>短期情绪</p></li>
<li><p>过于自信</p></li>
</ul>

<p>因为相对于自己存在的偏见，人们往往更容易发现他人的偏见。</p>

<blockquote>
<p>利弊清单法不能校正上述问题，但是 WRAP流程法可以做到</p>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>WRAP</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Widen your options（拓宽选择空间）</p></li>
<li><p>Redlity- test your assumptions（把假设放到现实中检验）</p></li>
<li><p>Attain distance before deciding（在做出决策前，留出一段距离来考虑）</p></li>
<li><p>Prepare to be wrong（做好出错的准备）</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>思维狭隘</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>青少年们易变得思维狭隘，这也就是阻碍决策的第一个因素。</p></li>
<li><p>事实证明，在做决定时，机构和组织的行为倒是跟青少年的很相像。</p></li>
<li><p>青少年陷入思维狭隘之中。他们意识不到选项的存在。</p></li>
<li><p>可供我们选择的选项常常比预期的要丰富得多。</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>为什么我们会陷入思维狭隘之中？</strong></p>

<p>专注于目前的选择意味着对其他选项视而不见。</p>

<p><strong>我们如何避开思维狭隘？</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>考虑机会成本。</p></li>
<li><p>试试“消失选项测试”：现有的选择消失后你会怎么做？</p></li>
<li><p>身在其外——作为一个决策顾问，更容易发现思维的狭隘。“是或否”决定应该引起重视。</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>多目标追踪</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>多目标追踪使我们时刻保持自省。</p></li>
<li><p>那些考虑多个选择的执行者能更快地做出决定。</p></li>
<li><p>极端的多目标追踪是有害的</p></li>
<li><p>最明智的决定可能是将预防心态的谨慎和进取心态的热情结合在一起</p></li>
<li><p>当生活提供给我们“非此即彼”的选择时，我们应该勇敢地去探索是否存在一个“两者都选”的正确答案。</p></li>
<li><p>多目标追踪等于同时思考一个以上的选择。</p></li>
<li><p>当你同时考虑多个选择的时候，你认识到了问题的“形状”。</p></li>
<li><p>考虑数个选择可能引起决策瘫痪，因此我们只可再多考虑一至两个选择。这样，得到的收益是巨大的。</p></li>
<li><p>警惕&quot;虚假选择&quot;。</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>当你需要更多选择，却感觉陷入僵局时，那就去寻找已经帮你解决了问题的人吧。</strong></p>

<p><strong>寻找已经帮你解决了问题的人</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>从外部寻找：竞争分析，基准衡量，最优方法。</p></li>
<li><p>从内部寻找：找到你的亮点。</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>为了变得主动，请将你的精细选择编入决策的&quot;问题列表&quot;。</strong></p>

<p><strong>审核清单阻止人们犯错误，问题列表刺激新思路的产生。</strong></p>

<p><strong>第三个寻找创意的地方：着眼于远处。</strong></p>

<p><strong>假设积极意图和写婚姻日记是被心理学家称作“考虑相反的情况”的两个例</strong></p>

<p><strong>三种对抗证实倾向的方法：</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>第一，我们可以使他人更容易地提出反对意见</p></li>
<li><p>第二，我们可以提出更有可能使相反信息显现的问题</p></li>
<li><p>第三，我们可以通过考虑相反情况的方法来对自己进行核查</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>证实倾向指的是搜寻到的正是我们初步假设的信息（常常是有利于自己的）</strong></p>

<p><strong>警告：在角色划分明确的情况下，探究性问题可能产生事与愿违的效果。</strong></p>

<p><strong>非证实倾向的极端形式：我们能否强迫自己考虑直觉的对立面？</strong></p>

<p><strong>我们甚至可以通过故意犯错来测试自己的假设。</strong></p>

<p><strong>因为我们会自然地去寻找自我证实的信息，所以我们需要训练自己从相反的原则考虑问题。</strong></p>

<p><strong>当我们依据评论做出决定时，我们便是在承认两件事情：</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>我们自身搜集产品真实情况的能力是有限的，而且我们的判断还会受限于制造公司对产品信息的失真传达。</p></li>
<li><p>基于上述原因，用他人的平均评价弥补自己印象的不足就是更明智的行为。</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>心理学家对同一情境中的“内视观点”和“外视观点”进行过如下区分。</strong></p>

<p><strong>内视观点是指在考虑决定时，从处于我们聚光灯内的信息——自己对情况的印象和评价——来获得结论。</strong></p>

<p><strong>相比之下，外视观点则能够忽略具体细节，从大局进行分析。</strong></p>

<p><strong>适当的情绪恰是我们做出明智之选所必需的。</strong></p>

<p><strong>我们对&quot;平均值&quot;的信任常常会超过我们的直觉——但却做不到应该相信的程度。</strong></p>

<p><strong>内视观点等于对自身所在的特定环境的评价。外视观点等于在类似于我们这样的情况下，事情通常是如何呈现的。外视观点更为精确，但绝大多数人会向内视观点倾斜。</strong></p>

<p><strong>如果你无法为自己的选择找到“基本比率”，那就去找专家。</strong></p>

<p><strong>专家们擅长评估基本比率，但在预测方面却不在行。</strong></p>

<p><strong>特写”可以增添外视观点所缺少的内容。</strong></p>

<p><strong>为了得到最好的信息，我们应该用缩小和放大法。</strong></p>

<p><strong>我发现找到任何一个人类要表现明显优于粗略的外推算法的领域是不可能的。</strong></p>

<p><strong>怎么专家知道的如此多，他们的预测能力却如此差劲？</strong></p>

<p><strong>尝试应该被当成一种加快搜集可靠信息的方法，而不是一种减缓我们做出值得全心投入的决策的方法。</strong></p>

<p><strong>我们已经接触到了三种对应策略。</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>第一，我们必须勤于想出搜集信息的方法，提出反面问题和考虑相反的情况；</p></li>
<li><p>第二，我们必须寻找正确的信息：用缩小法去寻找那些总结他人经验的基本比率，用放大法去获取对现实更加细微的印象；</p></li>
<li><p>第三， 尝试（ ooching）就等于做小实验以测试我们的理论。</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>尝试</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>尝试的方法很有用，因为我们在预测未来方面做得很糟。</p></li>
<li><p>企业家会很自然地尝试</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>警告：尝试在需要做出承诺的情形中，不能使我们达到预期效果。</strong></p>

<p><strong>常见的聘用错误：我们试图通过面试对成功做出预测</strong></p>

<p><strong>为什么我们要在可以了解的时候去猜测？在做出决策前，留出一段距离来考虑</strong></p>

<p><strong>使用 10— 10— 10方法，就意味着我们要以三个不同的时间范围为基础对决定进行考量：从现在算起的 10分钟后，我们对这一决定会有什么样的感觉？再过 10个月后呢？ 10年后呢？</strong></p>

<p><strong>对某物的熟悉不会令人们产生轻视的情绪，它更可能使人们心满意足。几十年来，心理学家们一直在研究这一被称为“曝光效应”（ mere exposure）的现象</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>发现看到刺激物的次数越多，人们对刺激物的好感度就越高。</p></li>
<li><p>这种对于现状的偏爱是另一种认知偏见。它被称为损失厌恶（ loss aversion），指的是人们发现相较于收益带来的快乐，损失带来的痛苦更大</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>组织内部的决策容易受到强有力的情感扭曲的支配。</strong></p>

<p><strong>维持现状偏见（ Status- Quo Bias）也许在大型官僚制的组织中最为明显。</strong></p>

<p><strong>解释水平理论”（ construal- level theory）的相对新型的心理学研究领域显示，距离我们面临的问题越远，我们就越能更清楚地看到问题最重要的方面。</strong></p>

<p><strong>研究人员发现，从实质上讲，我们为他人提出的建议常取决于唯一一个最重要的因素，而我们自己的思绪却在各种变量中翻腾。</strong></p>

<p><strong>由此可知，我们给他人提出的建议具有两大优点：</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>它自然地会把最重要的因素放在决策中的优先位置进行考虑，</p></li>
<li><p>而且它还弱化了短期情绪。 </p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>瞬时的情绪诱使我们做出那些在长远看来是坏决定的决定。</strong></p>

<p><strong>为了克服使我们分心的短期情绪，我们要学会留出些距离。</strong></p>

<p><strong>10— 10— 10方法迫使我们像考虑当前情绪一样对未来情绪进行充分考虑，从而使“留出距离”得以实现。</strong></p>

<p><strong>我们的决定常常被两种微妙的短期情绪改变：</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>曝光效应：我们喜欢自己所熟悉的东西。</p></li>
<li><p>损失厌恶：损失让人痛苦，收益让人愉快，而前者的程度要更大一些。</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>损失厌恶与曝光效应相结合的结果是维持现状偏见。</strong></p>

<p>通过一个观察者的角度看自身所处的情况，我们可以留出这个距离。</p>

<p>在个人做决策时，最有力的问题可能会是：“如果面临这种情况的是我最好的朋友，那我会告诉他/她如何去做？”</p>

<p>《从优秀到卓越》（ Good to Great）一书的作者——会建议我们建立一个“停止做的事情”的清单。</p>

<p>他的顾问让他思考，如果他接到了两个改变人生的电话，他会怎么做。</p>

<p>在第一个电话中，他会得知自己继承了 2 000万美元，并且无任何附带条件。</p>

<p>而第二个电话则是告知他患上了一个罕见而难以治愈的疾病，他只剩下 10年的寿命。</p>

<p><strong>平复短期情绪并不总能令一个决定变得容易。</strong></p>

<p><strong>核心价值观</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>一个令人苦恼的决定常常是你的核心价值观遭遇冲突的时候。核心价值观：长期的情感价值、目标和志向。</p></li>
<li><p>将你的核心价值观视为神圣的东西，在解决现在以及未来遇到的困境时，就可以更容易一些。</p></li>
<li><p>遗憾的是，建立你的优先顺序与遵守它们是不同的。</p></li>
<li><p>空出时间来实践我们的核心价值观，我们必须对次级优先的事情发起攻势。</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>预想式</strong>回顾似乎能鞭策我们产生更多的深刻见解，因为它迫使我们在今天以及一件确定发生的未来事件之间的空白处添上内容（截然不同于一个猜测某件事情是否会发生的更加难以明确的过程）。</p>

<p><strong>未来不是一个“点”——一个我们必须预测的简单场景，它是一个范围。</strong>我们应该书档未来，对从非常坏到非常好的大范围内的结果进行考虑。</p>

<p><strong>事前验尸方式</strong></p>

<p>在为较矮的那片书档做准备时，我们需要进行事前验尸。“已经过去一年了。我们的决策彻底失败了。它失败的原因是什么？”</p>

<p><strong>预演</strong></p>

<p>为较高的那片书档做准备时，我们需要进行预演。“已经过去一年了。我们变成了英雄。我们准备好获得成功了吗？”</p>

<p>为了应对无法预见的结果，我们可以采用一个“安全系数”。</p>

<p>对问题做出预期能够帮助我们处理问题。 “真实工作预览”：预先揭示一份工作的缺点，给人们“注射了不满意疫苗”。</p>

<p><strong>通过书档法——同时对逆境和成功做出预期和准备——我们预先做好了有利于自己决定的布局。</strong></p>

<p><strong>绊网（tripwire）</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>有个方法是设定最后期限，而这是绊网最为常见的形式。</p></li>
<li><p>在设定最后期限和测量评估方法之外的另一个策略是，用一个“隔断”（partition）来充当绊网。</p></li>
<li><p>但是隔断却在做一些不同的事情：它在设定界限。</p></li>
<li><p>在生活中，我们会自然地进入“自动驾驶”状态，将以前的决定搁置一旁，不对其进行检查。</p></li>
<li><p>一个绊网可以令我们清醒过来，并使我们意识到自己有个选择。</p></li>
<li><p>在变化缓慢进行的时候，绊网特别有用</p></li>
<li><p>受困于“自动驾驶状态”中的人们可以考虑最后期限和隔断。我们易于增加自己对糟糕决定的投入；隔断能帮助我们阻止这种做法。</p></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>实际上，绊网可以为冒险行为提供一个安全空间。它们：</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>规定了冒险行为的上限；</p></li>
<li><p>使你的精神获得平静，直至碰到“触发器”。</p></li>
</ul>

<p>许多有力的绊网是被模式识别的，而非日期、度量和预算所触发。</p>

<p>绊网可以提供一个宝贵的认识：我们有一个选择要做。</p>

<p><strong>妥协就像是个老笑话：“骆驼乃是由委员会制作的一匹马。”</strong></p>

<p><strong>程序正义</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>大量研究证实，在解释人们对一个决定的感受方面，程序正义非常重要。关键的不是结果，而是过程。</p></li>
<li><p>群体做出的决定有一个额外的负担：它们必须被人们视为公正的决定。</p></li>
<li><p>“讨价还价”——直至各方都可以接受最后的选择——有助于形成被人们视为公正的决定。</p></li>
<li><p>我们应该确保人们能感觉到判定过程是公正的。</p></li>
<li><p>一个可靠的方法可以帮助我们设法解决哪怕是最棘手的决定。</p></li>
<li><p>“流程”并非富有魅力，但它所能提供的信心却是珍贵的。</p></li>
</ul>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>读《1984》</title>
	  <link>//reading-1984</link>
	  <author>Tao He</author>
	  <pubDate>2018-07-16T02:20:12+08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//reading-1984</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>1984应该是我读的第一本英文原版小说，我其实不太喜欢看小说，汉语的我也很少看，但竟然每天在地铁上看，一个月下来竟然看完了，期间总会遇到生词，看不懂的长句，但竟然读出了惊叹，大有拍案叫绝的冲动，感受得到人物的绝望，恐惧，第一次，读着非母语写成的文字，生出了喟叹，感动。这些英文单词变得不那么疏离，它所描绘的情景人物变得栩栩如生，人物的落寞与心死都可透出纸面，感染到我。也许好的文字无论用什么语言表达都能直直抵人心吧！</p>

<p>有一些段落我在读的过程中记录了下来，现摘录如下：</p>

<p>BIG BROTHER IS WATCHING YOU</p>

<p>The telescreen received and transmitted simultaneously. Any sound that Winston made, above the level of a very low whisper, would be picked up by it, moreover, so long as he remained within the field of vision which the metal plaque commanded, he could be seen as well as heard. There was of course no way of knowing whether you were being watched at any given moment. How often, or on what system, the Thought Police plugged in on any individual wire was guesswork. It was even conceivable that they watched everybody all the time. But at any rate they could plug in your wire whenever they wanted to. You had to live—did live, from habit that became instinct—in the assumption that every sound you made was overheard, and, except in darkness, every movement scrutinized.</p>

<p>WAR IS PEACE
FREEDOM IS SLAVERY 
IGNORANCE IS STRENGTH</p>

<p>This was not illegal ( nothing was illegal, since there were no longer any laws), but if detected it was reasonably certain that it would be punished by death, or at least by twenty-five years in a forced-labor camp.</p>

<p>The horrible thing about the Two Minutes Hate was not that one was obliged to act a part, but, on the contrary,that it was impossible to avoid joining in. Within thirty seconds any pretence was always unnecessary. A hideous ecstasy of fear and vindictiveness, a desire to kill, to torture, to smash faces in with a sledge-hammer, seemed to flow through the whole group of people like an electric current, turning one even against one&#39;s will into a grimacing, screaming lunatic. And yet the rage that one felt was an abstract, undirected emotion which could be switched from one object to another like the flame of a blow lamp. </p>

<p>Nearly all children nowadays were horrible.What was worst of all was that by means of such organizations as the Spies they were systematically turned into ungovernable little savages, and yet this produced in them no tendency whatever to rebel against the discipline of the Party. On the contrary, they adored the Party and everything connected with it. The songs, the processions, the banners, the hiking, the drilling with dummy rifles, the yelling of slogans, the worship of Big Brother--it was all a sort of glorious game to them. All their ferocity was turned outwards, against the enemies of the State, against foreigners, traitors, saboteurs, thought-criminals. It was almost normal for people over thirty to be frightened of their own children. And with good reason, for hardly a week passed in which The Times did not carry a paragraph describing how some eavesdropping little sneak -- &quot;child hero&quot; was the phrase generally used — had overheardsome compromising remark and denounced its parents to the Thought Police.</p>

<p>Years ago — how long was it? Seven years it must be — he had dreamed that he was walking through a pitch-dark room. And someone sitting to one side of him had said as he passed: &quot;We shall meet in the place where there is no darkness.&quot; It was said very quietly, almost casually — a statement, not a command. He had walked on without pausing. What was curious was that at the time, in the dream, the words had not made much impression on him. It was only later and by degrees that they had seemed to take on significance. He could not now remember whether it was before or after having the dream that he had seen O&#39;Brien for the first time, nor could he remember when he had first identified the voice as O&#39;Brien&#39;s. But at any rate the identification existed. It was O&#39;Brien who had spoken to him out of the dark.
Winston had never been able to feel sure — even after this morning&#39;s flash of the eyes it was still impossible to be sure whether O&#39;Brien was a friend or an enemy. Nor did it even seem to matter greatly. There was a link of understanding between them, more important than affection or partisanship.&quot;We shall meet in the place where there is no darkness,&quot; he had said. Winston did not know what it meant, only that in some way or another it would come true.</p>

<p>It was always at night. The arrests invariably happened at night. The sudden jerk out of sleep, the rough hand shaking your shoulder, the lights glaring in your eyes, the ring of hard faces round the bed. In the vast majority of cases there was no trial, no report of the arrest. People simply disappeared, always during the night. Your name was removed from the registers, every record of everything you had ever done was wiped out, your one-time existence was denied and then forgotten. You were abolished, annihilated: vaporized was the usual word. </p>

<p>Thoughtcrime does not entail death: thoughtcrime IS death. </p>

<p>Tragedy,he perceived,belonged to the ancient time,to a time when there were still privacy,love and friendship,and when the members of a family stood by one another without needing to know the reason.</p>

<p>Who controls the past controls the future, who controls the present controls the past.</p>

<p>“Don&#39;t you see that the whole aim of Newspeak is to narrow the range of thought?In the end we shall make thought-crime literally impossible, beacuse there will be no words in which to express it. Every concept that can ever be needed will be expressed by exactly one word, with its meaning rigidly defined and all its subsidiary meanings rubbed out and forgotten. Already,in the Eleventh Edition, we&#39;re not far from that point. But the process will still be continuing long after you and I are dead. Every year fewer and fewer words,and the range of consciousness always alittle smaller. Even now, of course there&#39;s no reason or excuse for committing thought-crime. It&#39;s merely a question of self-discipline, reality-control. But in the end there won&#39;t be any need even for that. The Revolution will be complete when the language is perfect. Nespeak is Ingsoc and Ingsoc is Newspeak,” he added with a sort of mystical satisfaction. &quot;Has it ever occurred to you, Winston, that by the year2050, at the very latest, not a single human being will be alive who could understant such a conversation as we are having now?&quot;</p>

<p>In some ways she was far more acute than Winston, and far less susceptible to Party propaganda. Once when he happened in some connexion to mention the war against Eurasia, she startled him by saying casually that in her opinion the war was not happening. The rocket bombs which fell daily on London were probably fired by the Government of Oceania itself, “just to keep people frightened”. </p>

<p>&#39;You&#39;re only a rebel from the waist downwards,&#39; he told her.</p>

<p>Throughout recorded time, and probably since the end of the Neolithic Age, there have been three kinds of people in the world, the High, the Middle, and the Low. They have been subdivided in many ways, they have borne countless different names, and their relative numbers, as well as their attitude towards one another, have varied from age to age: but the essential structure of society has never altered. Even after enormous upheavals and seemingly irrevocable changes, the same pattern has always reasserted itself, just as a gyroscope will always return to equilibrium, however far it is pushed one way or the other.</p>

<p>In one combination or another, these three super-states are permanently at war, and have been so for the past twenty-five years. War, however, is no longer the desperate, annihilating struggle that it was in the early decades of the twentieth century. It is a warfare of limited aims between combatants who are unable to destroy one another, have no material cause for fighting and are not divided by any genuine ideological difference This is not to say that either the conduct of war, or the prevailing attitude towards it, has become less bloodthirsty or more chivalrous. On the contrary, war hysteria is continuous and universal in all countries, and such acts as raping, looting, the slaughter of children, the reduction of whole populations to slavery, and reprisals against prisoners which extend even to boiling and burying alive, are looked upon as normal, and, when they are committed by one&#39;s own side and not by the enemy, meritorious. But in a physical sense war involves very small numbers of people, mostly highly-trained specialists, and causes comparatively few casualties. The fighting, when there is any, takes place on the vague frontiers whose whereabouts the average man can only guess at, or round the Floating Fortresses which guard strategic spots on the sea lanes. In the centres of civilization war means no more than a continuous shortage of consumption goods, and the occasional crash of a rocket bomb which may cause a few scores of deaths. War has in fact changed its character. </p>

<p>The war, therefore, if we judge it by the standards of previous wars, is merely an imposture. It is like the battles between certain ruminant animals whose horns are set at such an angle that they are incapable of hurting one another. But though it is unreal it is not meaningless. It eats up the surplus of consumable goods, and it helps to preserve the special mental atmosphere that a hierarchical society needs. War, it will be seen, is now a purely internal affair. In the past, the ruling groups of all countries, although they might recognize their common interest and therefore limit the destructiveness of war, did fight against one another, and the victor always plundered the vanquished. In our own day they are not fighting against one another at all. The war is waged by each ruling group against its own subjects, and the object of the war is not to make or prevent conquests of territory, but to keep the structure of society intact. The very word &#39;war&#39;, therefore, has become misleading. It would probably be accurate to say that by becoming continuous war has ceased to exist. The peculiar pressure that it exerted on human beings between the Neolithic Age and the early twentieth century has disappeared and been replaced by something quite different. The effect would be much the same if the three super-states, instead of fighting one another, should agree to live in perpetual peace, each inviolate within its own boundaries. For in that case each would still be a self-contained universe, freed for ever from the sobering influence of external danger. A peace that was truly permanent would be the same as a permanent war. This -- although the vast majority of Party members understand it only in a shallower sense -- is the inner meaning of the Party slogan: War is Peace</p>

<p>Between life and death, and between physical pleasure and physical pain, there is still a distinction, but that is all. Cut off from contact with the outer world, and with the past, the citizen of Oceania is like a man in interstellar space, who has no way of knowing which direction is up and which is down. The rulers of such a state are absolute, as the Pharaohs or the Caesars could not be. They are obliged to prevent their followers from starving to death in numbers large enough to be inconvenient, and they are obliged to remain at the same low level of military technique as their rivals; but once that minimum is achieved, they can twist reality into whatever shape they choose.</p>

<p>War, it will be seen, is now a purely internal affair. In the past, the ruling groups of all countries, although they might recognize their common interest and therefore limit the destructiveness of war, did fight against one another, and the victor always plundered the vanquished. In our own day they are not fighting against one another at all. The war is waged by each ruling group against its own subjects, and the object of the war is not to make</p>

<p>The aims of these three groups are entirely irreconcilable. The aim of the High is to remain where they are. The aim of the Middle is to change places with the High. The aim of the Low, when they have an aim — for it is an abiding characteristic of the Low that they are too much crushed by drudgery to be more than intermittently conscious of anything outside their daily lives —is to abolish all distinctions and create a society in which all men shall be equal. Thus throughout history a struggle which is the same in its main outlines recurs over and over again. For long periods the High seem to be securely in power, but sooner or later there always comes a moment when they lose either their belief in themselves or their capacity to govern efficiently, or both. They are then overthrown by the Middle, who enlist the Low on their side by pretending to them that they are fighting for liberty and justice. As soon as they have reached their objective, the Middle thrust the Low back into their old position of servitude, and themselves become the High. Presently a new Middle group splits off from one of the other groups, or from both of them, and the struggle begins over again. Of the three groups, only the Low are never even temporarily successful in achieving their aims. It would be an exaggeration to say that throughout history there has been no progress of a material kind. Even today, in a period of decline, the average human being is physically better off than he was a few centuries ago. But no advance in wealth, no softening of manners,no reform or revolution has ever brought human equality a millimetre nearer. From the point of view of the Low, no historic change has ever meant much more than a change in the name of their masters.</p>

<p>Part of the reason for this was that in the past no government had the power to keep its citizens under constant surveillance. The invention of print, however, made it easier to manipulate public opinion, and the film and the radio carried the process further. With the development of television, and the technical advance which made it possible to receive and transmit simultaneously on the same instrument, private life came to an end. Every citizen, or at least every citizen important enough to be worth watching, could be kept for twentyfour hours a day under the eyes of the police and in the sound of official propaganda, with all other channels of communication closed. The possibility of enforcing not only complete obedience to the will of the State, but complete uniformity of opinion on all subjects, now existed for the first time.</p>

<p>It had long been realized that the only secure basis for oligarchy is collectivism. Wealth and privilege are most easily defended when they are possessed jointly. The so-called &quot;abolition of private property&quot; which took place in the middle years of the century meant, in effect, the concentration of property in far fewer hands than before: but with this difference, that the new owners were a group instead of a mass of individuals. Individually, no member of the Party owns anything, except petty personal belongings. Collectively, the Partyowns everything in Oceania, because it controls everything, and disposes of the products as it thinks fit.</p>

<p>&quot; When you make love you&#39;re using up energy; and afterwards you feel happy and don&#39;t give a damn for anything. They can&#39;t bear you to feel like that. They want you to be bursting with energy all the time. All this marching up and down and cheering and waving flags is simply sex gone sour.&quot; ... There was a direct, intimate connection between chastity and political orthodoxy. 
...The family could not actually be abolished, and, indeed, people were encouraged to be fond of their children in an almost the old-fashioned way. The children, on the other hand, were systematically turned against their parents and taught to spy on them and report their deviations...It was a device by means of which everyone could be surrounded night and day by informers who knew him intimately.</p>

<p>He had won the victory over himself. He loved Big Brother.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>政策与民意</title>
	  <link>//policy-and-people-will</link>
	  <author>Tao He</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-11-24T02:20:12+08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//policy-and-people-will</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>政策，这个词在我们这个国家被普遍使用，几乎人人理解其含义，就连目不识丁的老农都会说出这样的话：“中央又出新政策了”，这个词我们是如此的熟悉，以至于我们常常都不会去想政策到底是什么，它是如何制定出来的？我们普通老百姓是否影响到了政策的制定？ 也许一般的理解是老百姓哪能影响到政策的制定，照老农的说法，那是中央出的政策，和我们这些小老百姓有啥关系，这么理解也没错，毕竟在我们这个国家，显然普通民众的权利实在有限，但是此处我并不想讨论政策的制定和出台，只是想探究已出台的，与民生息息相关的这些个政策，到底有没有民意的基础，民意是否影响到了政策的制定？ 要讨论这个问题，拿北京这几年的一些政策法规的例子最好不过了。</p>

<p>先说北京房子的限购，以及相关联的所谓的抑制房价过快上涨的各种政策手段，但凡有点经济学常识的人，都知道这些政策只会让房价更高，增加更多购房成本，但是这些政策还是出来了，政府有什么考虑我们不得而知，但是呼吁出台这些政策的民意绝对是存在的，这种呼声绝对不是少数，甚至有一些经济学家也在为这种政策摇旗呐喊，就无怪乎普通民众有这种诉求了。而这种大多数的诉求就成了普遍的民意基础，使这种违背基本经济学常识的政策不再是空中楼阁。房价的这个例子也许会因房价问题本来就错综复杂而变得更加说不清道不明，那可以再看一例：网约车。</p>

<p>在网约车还没有出现之前，我们的选择只有出租车和所谓的黑车，出行体验如何，只要在烈日和寒风中打过出租车的人都应该知道那是一种什么样的服务，自从有了网约车，如滴滴打车后，我们的出行体验有了巨大的改观。那种打车难的时代一去不复返了，但是好景不长，很快政策对网约车出台了一系列不友好政策，之后的打车体验明显不如之前，这种政策也明显违背市场经济规律，但是它照样堂而皇之的出台了，你以为这是出租车利益集团的反扑，但是别忘了，这背后还有很坚实的民意基础，网约车存在的一些问题总是能让很多普通民众认为监管是必须的，政府必须介入才能让他们有安全感，但其实这些问题难道出租车就不存在吗？不希冀于市场竞争，而总幻想依赖政府强力，这种普遍的认知构成了一种可怕的，无望的民意，渗透进我们生活中的方方面面。</p>

<p>这种可怕的认知，在今年年底北京出现的两件重要的事情中更是体现的淋漓尽致，也许这些政策普通民众并不能左右，但民众的普遍认知构成了民意基础，因为在大部分人的认知中并没有达成这样的共识：有些事只能交给市场，政府干预只会扰乱市场；私有财产神圣不可侵犯；贩夫走卒，不高端的人群也有公民权；这些在文明社会都普遍达成的共识并未深入人心。这些个看似荒谬的政策既是权力意志的体现，也少不了那可怕民意的影子。</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>I Do Not Know What I May Appear To The World</title>
	  <link>//I-do-not-know-what-I-may-appear-to-the-world</link>
	  <author>Tao He</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-06-09T01:20:00+08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//I-do-not-know-what-I-may-appear-to-the-world</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>作为“God”板块的第一篇，引用牛顿爵士的一段话来开启。</p>

<p>I do not know what I may appear to the world, but to myself I seem to have been only like a boy playing on the sea-shore, and diverting myself in now and then finding a smoother pebble or a prettier shell than ordinary, whilst the great ocean of truth lay all undiscovered before me.  </p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
